Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering Prayer And Prophecy In Jesus' Name
Come on. There is a challenge you are facing. You should learn to forgive.
Forgive this man because this is what is affecting your son.
Deliverance In Jesus' Name
Acting on the prophetic word, the following Sunday,
the woman returned to The SCOAN with her son
whom the prophecy had revealed had been negatively affected.
As Prophet T.B. Joshua ministered prayer to the congregation,
the power of the Holy Spirit tore down the kingdom of satan and set the captives free.
During the prayer, the woman who received the prophecy
cried out for God's mercy to speak for her son.
Man of God, he is an armed robber. Man of God, please help me.
Man of God, help me. He is an armed robber.
Man of God, help me deliver my son. He is a fraudster. He is into everything.
He refused to go to school. Man of God, help me.
He is addicted to drugs. Man of God, help me.
He is delivered in the name of Jesus Christ.
TESTIMONY TIME
My name is Mrs Eno Ekanem.
The person standing next to
me is my son Emmanuel Ekanem.
He's 27 years old.
Two Sundays ago, the man of God walked up to me and prophesied
that I had a challenge, that I
should forgive this man.
That that was the cause of
the problem I have with my son.
This man happens to be my husband for over 35 years.
Emmanuel is the last of four children.
He is the last.
Emmanuel has given us so much pain.
Emmanuel has been a child that
we wished he should have died
so that the family can have peace,
so that the family's name will not be in the mud.
The man in question is my husband
but he never played the role of a
father to them.
He sort of allowed everything to be on my shoulders.
The man of God actually saw my heart
because I have been pained, I've been living in pain.
He hurt me so much.
After the prophecy on that Sunday,
I was contemplating on calling him
because we had not seen him for a very long time,
we had not heard from him, his phone was switched off.
The whole of Sunday I said to myself that there was no need to call him
because we didn't know where
he was - whether he's dead or not.
I didn't want to have pain again.
But on Monday morning, I just woke up and the Spirit of God said, "Call him!"
I called Emmanuel. Lo and behold,
the line that had not been ringing rang.
And I screamed, "Emmanuel, where are you?"
He said, "Mummy, I'm around."
I said, "Can you come right
away to the Synagogue to see me".
That is how the prophecy came to pass immediately.
He came last week and received his own deliverance.
My name is Emmanuel Ekanem.
The person standing beside me is my mum.
I came to The SCOAN because I had the problem of stealing, smoking,
I was addicted to drugs, I was a fraudster - I did online fraud, credit card fraud.
Whatever thing that has to do with fraud, you just name it.
I was also involved with some friends
of mine who were into armed robbery.
This problem of mine started a very long time ago,
from when I was very young.
I was always very brilliant in school. I never even used to read for my exams.
I was always brilliant but I always
had this spirit of stealing,
taking what wasn't mine like phones, money - I would take people's money and phones.
I was always bringing
embarrassment to my family
because even in school, like in secondary school, I would steal someone's money
and they would have to call my parents to come to school.
So I was always bringing shame to my family.
That's how it had been from when I was even very little. Just making bad friends.
I was making bad friends by default,
I didn't even have to try hard.
Every friend I was making was bad.
I am actually from a very good home.
I didn't have any reason for doing all this.
I was sent to the best schools that you could think of.
I was even sent to Canada, I was in Canada as of 2009.
I gained admission into the University
of Manitoba in Winnipeg, Canada.
So that was where I got involved with credit-card fraud.
I made a lot of bad friends, I was into drugs,
I was smoking all the time, I wasn't
even going to school.
My mum would always send me
school fees to pay my school fees,
but I would always end up spending the money on drugs,
going to clubs and I wasn't going to school.
I'm also very good with computers.
Anything that has to do with computers - I can programme, I can do softwares and hacking,
whatever you can think of.
I was into credit card fraud.
I was cloning different credit
cards and different people's accounts.
So I was doing this over time.
There was this job that I did - this credit card job I did for 200,000 dollars.
I was the one that did everything.
I cloned the credit card, went
into the bank and withdrew this money.
My picture and everything was in the bank.
Prior to this time, I never used to go into the bank to do anything
but that very time I went to the bank.
I withdrew the money and the
police started looking for me in Canada.
Then I was trying to move to
a different city to just lay low.
So on trying to go, I actually got caught by the police,
and I was the first person they caught, and I told them the names
of five of my accomplices that did the credit card scam.
I noticed that most of the
people that I got arrested with
were given long jail terms
like 5 years, 10 years, 15 years.
All this while, my mom didn't know I was in jail.
I was the only one that they gave the option
of being deported back to Nigeria.
I don't even know why because
I didn't even have a lawyer at that time
that would represent me in court or anything.
At the end of the day, I was deported and that is how my mum found out
that I was not going to school
and I was living this life of crime.
When I got back to Nigeria, my mom actually tried.
She wanted to set me up with
a business, to do shows.
She gave me 7 million naira and a brand new hilux.
It was her vehicle at that time so upon coming back,
she gave me the car to be using around.
She lives in Abuja so I was in Abuja with her at that point in time.
So when she gave me the money
and the car,
I left Abuja and ran to Lagos
with two friends that I had just made.
They were into drugs - we were always smoking together, going to nightclubs and all that.
When we came down to Lagos, I started staying in a hotel until when the 7 million were exhausted.
I didn't have any money. I sold the hilux that my mum had given to me.
She had bought the hilux for 7.5 million.
I sold it for like 2.3 million naira -
way less than the value of the car.
All for just drugs, going to nightclubs, and staying in a hotel.
The money finished at the end of the day.
So I ran back to my mom in Abuja
and that was how it was going on and on.
Even one day I took her
cheque book and I wrote everything on it.
I forged her signature and I went to the bank.
They actually paid me the amount of 500,000 on the cheque book.
So that's what I was doing. And any time I did this, I would always run away.
When the money was exhausted, I would always run back.
So this was going on and on until my mum started having medical issues -
she was having high blood pressure.
She couldn't deal with me anymore.
So she told me that I should come down to Lagos and stay with my father
because my dad lives here in Lagos.
So I came to Lagos to stay with my dad, and it was just the same thing.
I was giving my dad stress. I would take his money and run away.
I wouldn't come back, mingle with bad friends, smoke, take drugs and everything.
I met some friends that were into armed robbery at a point here in Lagos.
They posed to me as internet fraudsters.
I thought maybe that was what they were into.
Later, I discovered that they were into armed robbery.
They initiated me into the gang
and I started going on operations with them.
That's how the thing just continued.
I was going on operations with my friends who were armed robbers.
We were actually carrying guns when going on these operations.
We were making so much money but
they were not giving me enough.
One of the members told me that if I continued,
I would start getting more money
as compared to when I just started going
out with them on robbery incidents.
I also was getting people totrust me.
Once they trusted me, I would take their properties and just run away.
I also deceived people because I would
tell people that my mum was very influential
and if they wanted to get visas to
travel abroad, they could give me the money,
then I would talk to my mum
and we would procure the visas for them.
I did this to three or four different people.
Some people gave me 1 million, 2 million,
1.5 million, and I would just run away with the money.
They would trace me back to my mom.
My mom would say that she hadn't seen me for months,
She didn't even know where I was or where I was sleeping.
That's how it was going on and on while
I was living with my dad here in Lagos.
Three weeks ago I took my
dad's phone and I went to sell it.
After selling my dad's phone,
he got angry with me.
He locked the house and told me that I shouldn't come back unless I came back with his phone.
He didn't know that I was
with his car keys at that point.
In the night, I went into the house, started the car, opened the gate quietly and drove the car out.
I didn't have a phone, I was just with the car.
I was sleeping inside the car.
At night, I would just park the
car somewhere that I felt was safe,
and I would just sleep there until the next morning - surviving then.
Two weeks ago on Sunday,
I had parked by a barber saloon.
There was a barber saloon by the side.
Then I saw the prophet's picture on the sliding door of the barber saloon
but I didn't put any meaning into it. That was where I was throughout that Sunday.
You mean, you saw a sticker
with Prophet T.B. Joshua's picture on it.
I saw a sticker with his picture
- a very big sticker with his picture there.
So that was where I was that Sunday. But I didn't really put any meaning into it.
In fact, that Sunday, I ran out of money, I didn't have money.
I was with the car. I was trying to sell the car
but for some reason, I was not getting anybody that was interested in buying it.
On that Sunday, I wanted to put my sim card in the phone - in any phone I could get
so that I could call those my
friends that were into armed robbery
and see if I could go with them on any operation.
Just to get little money because I was out of money.
So that Monday morning, I just spoke to the barber at the saloon.
I told him that the car had broken down. I needed to call someone to help me fix it.
So when I put my sim card in the phone, I didn't even dial any number.
The call that came in - it was my mum.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So at the very moment you placed the SIM card in that phone, your mom just called?
Yes.
And when was the last time you
had seen or spoken with her?
For over eight months I had not seen or spoken to her.
So when I saw the caller's number, I was very surprised.
When I picked the call, I thought
she was going to shout at me,
ask me where I was with the car and everything.
So when I picked the call, she asked me where I was.
I told her I was around in Lagos here.
I didn't even know she was also in Lagos.
She told me that I should start coming down here.
I told her I didn't have any money.
She told me I should find a way.
I should enter a taxi, whatever I could find and just come down here to The SCOAN.
So I came down here on that Monday.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Brother, we saw that on last week's Sunday, your mum cried out to Prophet T.B. Joshua
as he was moving around, praying for people
and we saw how he prayed for you in the power of the Holy Spirit.
Can you just describe what happened to you at that point.
At the point when the prophet touched me, I felt like - for 2 or 3 minutes I blacked out.
I didn't even know where I was at that point in time.
I didn't even know where I was, I was confused.
I was weak; everything was just
going on with me at the same time.
I was shivering in my bones,
I was cold, I was hot.
I was just feeling everything at that point in time.
And had you ever experienced anything like that before?
Never, never!
Many men of God had placed their hands on me.
When I went to church before, it didn't move me.
I always prayed for them to touch me
to see if I would fall or something like that.
But I never felt that strong force in me before.
I knew I was shivering in my body, I started feeling cold.
I started feeling things leaving me.
I was just feeling so strange that very day.
I felt like something was coming out of me, leaving me - my whole body, my legs and my hands.
I just thank God for my life because I'm
not even supposed to be living right now.
I'm just happy from the bottom of my heart.
Glory be to God and since that touch, just tell us - what are the changes you've seen in your life?
Before, it was always very hard for me to stay two or three hours without smoking or taking drugs.
But since that day up till now, it's been
a week and I haven't even gone near
cigarettes, drugs or anything pertaining to that.
So I just give God the glory.
Now, those people like me - I used to believe that there is a God -
a life without Jesus is more or less a wasted life.
We should always look for a way to do good and not do evil.
Always try and pick your friends and don't let your friends pick you
because if I had known Jesus earlier, I know that by now, I would have been somewhere -
greater than where I am today.
It has just been the devil all the way, right
from when I was very young.
I'm just happy that
Jesus has saved me through the prophet.
I'm glad.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Praise the Lord!
Actually, when I came here the day I left Abuja, I told God that I'm going to a final destination.
I told myself that there is no way I will leave The SCOAN without a testimony.
When the man of God walked up to me, I did not expect him to tell me to forgive this man.
I was hoping that he was going to ask me, "Where is your son",
like I have heard him ask other people.
But I was shocked!
That is to show that he saw my heart; I was in pain.
I can't deny that. I was so much in pain because the person
that was supposed to play the role of a father did not do that.
So I have been living in pain.
I have forgiven him, Man of God.
I have forgiven him.
My son - I speak as a mother - is not supposed to be alive today
because as a family, we had prayed for him to die.
The reason I'm saying this is that he caused us so much pain -
when I mean pain, I mean pain.
So much embarrassment and shame.
I cried, went to churches, fasted and prayed but nothing seemed to happen.
That was why I ran to The SCOAN.
I never used to watch Emmanuel TV.
A friend introduced me to this channel, and I started watching it.
I just left it on permanently in my bedroom.
People came to my house and asked, "Oh! You are now for Emmanuel TV, T.B. Joshua?"
I said, "Yes". - "Without even coming here?"
I said, "Yes. What I am seeing happening there, I believe it will happen to me too".
I even told a friend, "One day you will see me testify".
And today our mother
is indeed testifying to the glory of God.
Before he left for Canada, he first got admission as a child into King's College.
At King's College, he wasn't there up to a month.
One morning between 6 and 7am, we just saw him coming in.
He didn't have any shirt and shoes on him.
I believe most people know where King's College is located.
And we asked him, "Where are you coming from?"
He said, "From school".
"Without shirt, without shoes?"
I was scared; this boy was just 9 years old.
We took him back.
He was never in school -
one complaint after the other.
The father said we should
take him out of King's College.
I said, "How can I? This is a school where every parent
would want her their to be.
Why would I withdraw him from King's College?"
We now decided that that was the best thing to do.
We had to withdraw him from King's College.
Before taking him out of King's College, we had to look for a school that had the highest fence.
I personally came down to scout all private schools
to see which one had the highest fence that he would not scale.
We got one in Ikeja. He started school.
The same thing continued and I wondered, "What kind of a thing is this?"
They gave him corporal punishment for scaling the fence - a very high fence.
It continued but during WAEC, the school was shocked and surprised that he had the best results.
This was a boy that did not read, that was never in school.
The proprietress called us and said,
"Madam, let this boy go to a private university
so that his time will not be wasted".
Of all my children, he is the only
one that went to a private university.
He got admission into Babcock University.
He did not read for the exams, he just walked
into the exam hall and passed.
He started University.
He was not in school for one month.
The father would go to the school, go to a hospital and get a medical report that he's asthmatic.
That's why he ran away, he was in the hospital.
The father did that three times.
He did that, and the fourth time,
he said, "No, he's not doing it again!"
Just to cover up for your son?
Yes, it was a cover-up so that the school would take him back.
But the fourth time that he left the school, the father said that he was not going to do it again.
That's how he came back home. What to do with him, we didn't know.
We just did not know what do with him.
He was just there.
We just did not know what to do.
Each time he disappeared, he would do something.
At times, when I was in the car, I would be looking at those dust bins, in case I would see a corpse.
I would be looking at the roadside, hoping that I would see his dead body but it never happened.
One day in my office, I was making a photocopy of his WAEC results.
I was crying because the results were fantastic.
A friend just walked into my office.
She just met me, I couldn't hide.
She said, "Why are you crying?"
I just threw the result papers to her.
And she said, "What! This boy got this result?"
I said, "But he has refused to be in school".
She said, "Okay, we are going to send him out of the country. Maybe that will help him".
That is how his going to Canada came up.
Before you know it, he got admission.
Everything for him is always fast, fast.
He got admission. He left for Canada.
I would always visit him, go to the school.
I would take pictures. He would take me
to the school. We would take pictures.
He would say, "Mommy,
this is this, this is that". I would be happy.
I would return home,
not knowing that he was not in school.
That he was just deceiving me.
The next year I would go again
because I wanted to keep track.
I would go, he would just deceive me,
and I would return home.
So when it happened like that,
I came back one of the times.
We hadn't heard from him for a very long time.
And I was worried.
One day, a strange person just called and said that he was a lawyer
representing my son, that my son was in jail.
My God, and this was during Christmas.
We were all in Calabar - all of us on Christmas day.
I couldn't hold myself.
On a Christmas day, my son was in jail!
That's how the process of getting
him out came in.
The lawyer, I was not there.
To make a long story short, he was deported.
And it continued until what we are seeing today.
I give God the glory - the God of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
That is the God that I will worship.
I will worship that God until the
day I am called to rest.
Because that God has...
Mrs Eno Ekanem & Son
Prophecy/Deliverance Testimony
I didn't even know he was into armed robbery.
I'm hearing it for the first time.
I didn't know. I thought it was all these other ones.
I never knew he had joined armed robbers.
Even when I was shouting, "Man of God, help me! He is an armed robber",
I just wanted to say anything that entered my mouth.
I just wanted to attract the attention of the man of God.
I didn't know he was actually an armed robber.
When I went back to Abuja, I told his older sister,
when she said, "Mummy, we saw you shouting, 'Armed robber!'
Is Emma an armed robber?"
I said, "I just wanted to
get the man of God's attention".
Nobody in the family knew that he was an armed robber.
I just said it that day - until now.
But I give God the glory because
this God is a covenant keeping God.
Something had always told me that I was going to testify about this Emmanuel in a large congregation.
It is not today - over 10 years ago in my church,
something kept telling me that I was going to testify in a large congregation
but it never meant anything to me.
I thought because he's a
musician, he sings very well -
he has done a video with Pastor Ranky
as you see him standing here.
I thought maybe one day that large congregation or television would be
as I'm dancing in this video.
That was what was in my mind.
But I never knew that it was going to be in a congregation as large as this - worldwide.
So I give God all the glory.
I thank the man of God, Prophet TB Joshua.
God will continue to pour more anointing on you and you will take this generation to the next level.
I want to advise all other mothers -
it is not about you spoiling your child.
He was never a pampered child.
I don't know how to pamper children.
I never pampered him,
I treated him like every other child.
But we should know that the devil usually picks on a star in the family.
That is exactly what happened.
The devil decided to take my own star.
But today I have retrieved my star.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
I want to say here that
I am a member of the Apostolic Church.
I am a Deaconess. I've been a
Deaconess for close to 20 years.
You don't know where your salvation is.
This is a ministry, this Synagogue is a church I had always had a negative opinion about.
As I speak, I am sure most of my pastors will see me
because even the first day I came, and I got my prophecy, people called me from all over,
"Are you for T.B. Joshua now?" I said, "Yes! That this is where I can see my salvation".
And I thank God so much for using
the man of God to liberate my family
because I believe everything has turned around for our good.
I had always had a negative impression about the church -
even more than her; her own was even small.
Because even when she started watching Emmanuel TV in her room,
any time I was in Abuja in the house, she would always wake everybody up early in the morning,
at 5:00 am in the morning when I was still sleeping
because I would usually go to bed at 3 or 4 am.
At 5 am she would wake everybody up, that we should come for prayers.
She would spray the Morning Water on us every morning.
I was always angry, always pissed off.
I would be like, "Why are you just
always disturbing me every morning
because of this Emmanuel TV,
this Morning Water, this T.B. Joshua?"
Even when I was with her in Abuja, she told me a certain time that I would come here.
That day, we had serious arguments because I was telling her that I didn't believe there was God here,
that I didn't believe that this was where I would get my salvation or deliverance.
I've always felt that this was not a place of God.
But on coming here, It's a different story
I just thank God because most
people like me wouldn't believe.
But if they can just come - take that step of faith and come - they would surely be delivered.
I also want to use this medium
to say that I'm very sorry to my mum
for whatever pain and hurt
that I've caused her in the past,
and I want to promise her that she will be happy to have me as a son.
She will be proud of me one day.
Mum, I'm sorry!
Mrs Eno Ekanem & Son
Prophecy/Deliverance Testimony
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!